Hello,
everyone on channel nine it's really great to be here my name's mary jo
foley I do not work for microsoft I'm but I'm a microsoft
watcher email me all about microsoft-dot-com and I'm here interviewing
to of my favorite people from microsoft I've got
...guggenheim or the cheap of evangelist for microsoft and john
...who is the chiefly for microsoft.
We're going to talk a little bit about the keynote you guys just came off the stage it
was really exciting people in the audience,
you know, there's questions that people want to see code I think we answer that today
...and, I want to hear from each of
you kind of what your biggest take away it's like if people are here at builder watching
bill what do you really want them to take away the one big thing I'll start I think it, you know,
first offered cu closings today coming out kind of a pleasure to be interviewed by
I think there's, there's a couple things one is lots of times people to have this perception of all-or-nothing right
where it's either all microsoft
...somebody else...those days are gone it's not it's not a world
...all-or-nothing I think we try to show there's lots of different areas where we can add value and find
place to partner...spin-off might be windows it might be...might be the office graphic might be
...might be something but it's rare that we don't come across await...
find things to do so the days of ogg...and then too...like I think back to the roots
would like work with developers...actually have fun with it pretty good at it so, we're here to do that.
I think a couple other quick things clearly the company as I've
been there has really evolved its position on incorporating lots
of other technologies into solutions whether it's open-source third-party.
Services so many applications are actually today stitching
together these different components to create a great solution so we're pretty excited to
be able to show some of those examples and then show partners who are really using
our platform in that
...to deliver on it and clearly the other big one just the
ubiquity of data throughout the...I think just did a fantastic job kind-of highlighting the
importance of data not just as a way to collect information but really understand it...
I'm dying to ask you guys about what I think was one of the most interesting things
at the conference the announcement that microsoft's going out talking now to in
very developers and ios developers and trying to bring them into the windows tenfold
I'm curious like what do you...go...developers so we have been, yeah,
I mean...so what's the elevator pitch what do you go and say to
...android developer why they should come to the windows...I don't usually think of developers
is sort of an android developer...mobile developers of time
build apps for devices or their building apps for something specific
...the conversation comes down to a we have a great platform allows you to do some unique
...we actually have a volume and scale especially anything about windows ten
aggregating all devices together the...is how do we make it as easy as possible for-you to move
on to the platform and take advantage of it so if they've written coded and where they have...mobile app
where they've...iowa's app that's a potential bridge into the platform so usually the conversation
...a balance between let's talk about the scale the platform was talk about some of
...unique things we offer another...out the easiest way for you to get
onto the platform and then over time we talk about...you can do,
yeah, I mean often when we sat down with...
and ios developer and we've had the conversation that...just described there's often a little bit
of skepticism about old could we really do this so we've sat down with a number of folks
taking their code run it through the compiler generated that windows application and I think
for some people it's almost like a magic trick they're like no way I can't believe that
it's actually working...unimportant thing happens which is the
see the app now running on windows they see the potential they understand
all maybe this wouldn't maybe we could reduce my costa develop...so
...a lot of ways I think these bridges are the door openers
that enabled the conversation about what we could do with
that billion customers what we could do with the value-added features?
The question is this is something I'm hearing a lot from the existing microsoft
developers existing windows development community what.
I guess the question is why shouldn't they be afraid of you guys doing this so suddenly here come
all these android developers your come all these ios developers and now they're competing with these
people have been loyal to the platform and have been developed developing
for windows for years like what is their advantage...as a windows
will look at the end of the process we're really looking for great
windows applicationsuniversal windows platform gives you this
ability to create these apps that spans all of these different vices and
at the tool set that people have developed whether it be and dot net or
...all those are things that kind of show through now interestingly
...sat down with some of these folks...move some say entry code over some ios code
in many cases people look at this and I think, you know, I might want to
...user interface more natively to be able to take advantage of some of
that scaling capability because you guys are providing some incredible things
about, for example, different
input mods across these devices think about how tricky it is to build
and app that can run on the phone and on and xbox and be able to do that so they want
to take advantage of that toolkit I think the other...the other side of the
conversation is the things that people find the most interesting exciting like look at the conference follow
...incredible reception that requires universal windows apple ultimately so
the developers that are already there great dana headstart on moving on to
or across the various devices and...developers looked the more apps on the platform
better off the platform is the better it is the ecosystem rising tide raises all boats so I think
in our case is how do we get as many experiences that are users one on...platform and for requires
abridge to help people get their we feel pretty good that once they start there's other things are going to want to which
you know, sort of all say bring them further into the windows conversation are into that broader community I mean really
does have that the fundamental shift that's going on here is we're just trying to reach out to everybody
on every platform and make it easier we want them to be able to bring their code and
we're trying to get out of the mode that I think the industry
within for a while saying hey you must do things this way?
We've had this conversation privately before but...I'd love to hear you explain
more about what with windows ten...going to be more interesting to
developers all up what and it kinda comes down to money right like what do you
guys going to do with windows ten that you didn't do was seven and eight to help developers make
...first of all say it's important to say we want to help developers do what they care about for
their in some cases that's modernization has lots of bc access do other things so I think
the and people measure device let's take the money one first off you
want aggregated many users as possible so the ability to take the windows
ten for us the pc base which is our largest plus...plus xbox and be able to create
experience...step one is volume the second thing is actually getting them into the app... the interesting part
there's if you look at the phone people are used to going to a store on the phone and on xbox
to use the dashboard the trick now is with windows...on the desktop...the pc is how we get people
into the store there so that's what...showing off yesterday that ability to use the start...the
...there that help people find applications the ability to use
core tonic the ability to have a rotating tile for the store so I think we're working on doing over
time is making that the desktop or the pc as interesting in terms of going...the
finding apps as all the other devices so now you have an aggregation volume you have a
...or a...to try and get people into the app and then it's all about haven instruments
...we talked about the ability to do credit card building across the pc across all
devices you look at other payment instruments you look at different types of payment models I talked a little
bit wishes and today about the ability only for web experience based app in the store referral
programs so I think we're going to run the gamut from scale first getting into the app seconds
...modernization there.
...on that totally agree those are all the things that
developers look at were talking about money on the other side of the house there's a bunch of
technical capabilities that I think are increasingly exciting to people, for example,
the deep linking...showed from core
...a directly down into the app or that david
kevin showed right into the middle of the game having intelligence in the
system to be able to help you find gaps to be able to help you get your
day-to-day jobs done I think it's
...be an increasingly important part of a way people interact with our computers.
Kentucky to a few developers who
are a little bit skeptical about the universal platform...and here's what they
skeptic skeptical about they believe that you could do the one code once store
...believe all that but...skepticism is more about why what I want to
...and the example is, you know, someone who develops and app expressly
for windows phone or phones and they don't really see a case for putting it on xbox
are follow...or surface hub...so what do you
say that I mean what is it is that kind of well you don't have to...don't want
to or...at a case where you could kind of explain to them white
...like that it's a little bit above and I mean that we end up talking a lot of those
...you know, it's mobile volume first great let's have
that conversations talk about how we can do that picking up another device easily
...interesting maybe not the nice thing...we also allow them to keep their experience retreat your
ui elements are going to change...discretize but the nice...when you writer manifest or crater
manifest if you...you want to...xbox not...so you have the choice
...any sort of pick up the others for free value get into a if I'm really
...only what are the things we can think about so you take some of the stuff joseph,
you know, showing for machine learning on the back-end there's some things that...for photos,
for example, image recognition so how can we add value that might be different from that
universes store maybe it's on the as your side maybe it's on
the other pieces let's talk about new phones and what's going on the phone market so there's a variety of
conversations week-and-a-half your not required is not all-or-nothing
...decided devices you...so it depends on what.
And, decide I want machine learning with this...but I don't want
...version that's on different platforms absolutes you can pick and chose that
...not only that one of those things developers of...this is very important
is the ability to independently...those different platforms so,
for example, maybe they've advanced along way
...the phone but that same map might be really great for
say showing photo albums or other kinds of things on xbox.
But, you don't want to have to do all the testing and that kind of
stuff in and some of the other platforms you kinda get stuck doing
and all-or-nothing here we can manage that stuff independently I met I met with...developer
...well-known and they care about...and the casey's they want to tablet dc...feedback was
look phones interesting xbox inching let's do this really great first and it's nice
...I can do those others but it's not necessarily what I want to do
...like right that's...conversations to a great job your first if we can figure out.
As an example where this occurs all-time
is particularly around creative or editing
kind those tend to be on the pc and then often what ends up happening is that
...the versions on other platform
on xbox or on the phone to be more about the browsing experience of that.
Another thing I talked to a few people hear about that they were really excited about was bringing
one-thirty to...store I know it sounds like...several thousand those...there we love them
...you...the numbers from...iterate...huge but,
the question of getting a lot is how does that actually happened because I've heard some people say
sand boxing something aptly...he met we mentioned...the in the
...great but, what do you have to exchange as a developer...bringing?
...start what again at the primary thing that apathy is doing is
...providing a level of indirection into many of the system calls that
historically have wired app in deeply to the operating system and
that deep wiring can sometimes cause the system to become increasingly unstable
overtime so really this that what the...the container is giving you is that
...degree of isolation so that from a...I can...on install I
feel-good about the experience we're also doing a bunch of work to ensure that
when thirty-two code can then take advantage of the
new modern capabilities and that has
...that's been difficult before and one of the key is to that is actually to have a story
...so that all of those system api
which required to know what app is being used now those apps have a
...entity and they can make that the...culture the other piece that goes with
that is creating a store app so creating a manifest allowing
...doesn't have an appropriate content dinner things if you want so there's the technical side of
...enabling use of the new api...protecting system for not running well and
...protecting the end-user from inappropriate content and that sort of what the...brought...the...
Another question on the store up that is both
...question hra about things as they stand now and things with
...sent out so especially
...windows phone and I'm a windows phone user I'm going to the three-person.
I I'm worried because I'm seeing some apps disappear from the store things like chase and
bank of america like very key apps and I am wondering what you guys think you
can do that pringles apps...
Let's say goes...we talked about we talked pretty regularly it's a good conversation banks
are interesting category where they have a lot of regulatory compliance
so the notion of keeping an app where a is not have...high-volume as others and
...they know we're going to windows can and...other options that's sort of the role
conversation there so the conversations we have it's we we're not happy with loosing from
...I wrote user both of their from the...by the same time the conversation we
move to is what's the right model for the go forward so our energy right now with all
developers what's...go forward we talked bankamerica chase pretty regularly so,
that's the dialogue which is I think they see the value in particular around the website if you look at
banks they do it but they have these great web experiences the notion of responsive design
web-based it just makes sense for them so the question is how
we go forward and we bridge between now and then sometimes we lose a few but the goal now
some of them forward and get to windows...and use things they would actually do anyway because
some people ask me about it they always say why does...microsoft just
...them or if they can give them developers to do the apps for the but certainly the case
...that way right now I mean...the...folksy
...regulate the notion of keeping...app going...putting investment against when,
you know, you're going to change to a different one...it's a trade-off resources which we all make and
...we help...provide developer...developers...one but it's just a logical
a tradeoff that we all make the business decision right and, they're still good partners still working with
...get...of...together thing...take some listener
...venture...people watching live-action...
their semitic questions on reddit also I am
...question you...who wants to know about universal apps and he
said yesterday there was really no mention
...javascript html five
...we answered the samoa today we heard it on the keynote a
gallery?
He's wondering about how microsoft's...javascript html five-point jasper when
ten universe...we'll place where does that look
what it again go back to that conversation about people...code we...help you get to the
...one of the bridges that we announced yesterday and we really focused on a
lot today was that ability to take web content.
Turn that into and app with this new wthree
really see manifest of but even more importantly when that app
is running that javascript is running inside the app it can reach out to
...to the...api is and it can do things like
...and notifications...we showed that today right we're very committed to this,
you know, we've just back to some of these...loud...conversation...so we...a lot of
...on the other...there's a lot of people who think...web or
app and having the opportunity say hey I can have my web experience become an advocate that
code the same is actually a very good comprehensive so we html five javascript
sort-of or many the...a great example in the bank conversation is
...web apps can be used for a lot of that but guess what when you
...go do that check...gotta be able to call out to the camera and that's where this whole
new web bridge really gives you the our to build those can apps...talked about one today as well
...great you...do that audio listening that's a web app using the audio listening.
...what's to another question
...juggler asks...I ever be able to sell...forms...
Look, to the...could be ingested as a...thirty-two app yes
...the same conversation we had earlier there's work you have to...technical side you have to know
...manifested all the rules but there's nothing that sort of separates out when forbes says no that
we're now I just want to put a copy on just that everybody understands in order to
run that when thirty-two code it requires some of the desktop subsystems so you
should expect, for example, that when forms app is going to run, for example, on a raspberry
pie it does it does separate the apps that we can bring on
...platforms from ones...think about as a universal windows platform
...because if I go to the following which runs a different processor
around the subsystems not necessarily going to work there so that's I think
...john's point you can get it was...over...you may not be across...and that said
we're hearing a lot of excitement from the from developers about disability take
their when thirty-two apps and bringing them to the apps for.
A related question for me is you guys talk so much these days now about
opensource and even make it part of your key notes and...integrating
and various places and tolls you're working with that community and I'm kinda curious
what do you get out of that like I understand in some ways
wide microsoft is doing this but.
That's kind of the motivation for you guys getting involved here you are you hoping
to get people who have kind of ignore the microsoft platform because you aren't
...it...to the platform versus something
different I don't think there's anything other than the most basic.
Fact that a lot of people leverage open-source can technologies to go build their
application right so if we for some reason had this view no,
we don't want open-source technologies on a platform I think...making it very hard for
people to advance the other thing that we're seeing is just a mass amount of innovation in the
open-source community I talked about javascript frameworks today I mean the
...of advance and sophistication even if you were to go
back five years ago there was no angular there was no amber there is no react
...level of excitement...energy that the community is putting into these
open-source projects we love being part of that you guys just have this great conversation with
chris from get have about how are you from his perspective it's just been
kinda mind-blowing working with microsoft and seen the transition.
He was kind of...he's like often when I want to tell people about how you to go do
something opensource projects you guys are actually pretty good example these
days which I can't it's hard for me...imagine...that, yeah,...
...I think...you know,
...return building burgess right but is about meeting developers where they are the world is so complex
today there...so many more places to be so saying hey you can only go this way...doesn't work that
...on build...history of work developers.
You guys were out-of-town but I think we're a quick and I have to...you show up your
sure all right steve because we're all...moi I
got some comments last year of my rugby years this year I did a custom yet and awesome this was
kind of fun so I think I'll keep...next year the only...my head right now is
...deal with account extra on-the-record...have no that's my teenage years working
Thank you.